<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lunar-linux.org//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://lunar-linux.org//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-04T21:48:37-03:00</updated><id>https://lunar-linux.org//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lunar Linux</title><subtitle>Lunar is an advanced source-based Linux distribution.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">contact</title><link href="https://lunar-linux.org//0004/04/03/contact.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="contact" /><published>0004-04-03T23:59:12-04:14</published><updated>0004-04-03T23:59:12-04:14</updated><id>https://lunar-linux.org//0004/04/03/contact</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lunar-linux.org//0004/04/03/contact.html">&lt;p&gt;Lunar is entirely volunteer based, but we make every effort to be available to talk with. If we’re not there, please leave a message and be patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-column flex-row-l items-center justify-around font-space tc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;br3 pv3 ph4 f3 white mw6 link bg-animate hover-bg-navy&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/libera-white.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Internet Relay Chat&quot; class=&quot;w-50&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;#lunar&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;br3 pv3 ph4 f3 white mw6 link bg-animate hover-bg-navy&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/discord-white.svg&quot; alt=&quot;discord&quot; class=&quot;w-50&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;#lunar&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;br3 pv3 ph4 f3 white mw6 link bg-animate hover-bg-navy&quot; href=&quot;mailto:#&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/email-white.svg&quot; alt=&quot;email&quot; class=&quot;w-50&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;info@lunar-linux.org&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Lunar is entirely volunteer based, but we make every effort to be available to talk with. If we’re not there, please leave a message and be patient. #lunar #lunar info@lunar-linux.org</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">about</title><link href="https://lunar-linux.org//0000/12/31/about.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="about" /><published>0000-12-31T23:59:12-04:14</published><updated>0000-12-31T23:59:12-04:14</updated><id>https://lunar-linux.org//0000/12/31/about</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lunar-linux.org//0000/12/31/about.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This part is important - who are we trying to attract? Lunar can be good for many people, but we need a focus. Can beginners install and maintain Lunar? Do we want developers and sysadmins looking for detailed control over their system? Users with older computers looking to optimize their system? Distro hoppers looking for something new?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do we explain what makes Lunar different from other distros? Are we a de-bloated version of Gentoo? Are we an advanced version of Linuxfromscratch?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;sample text below:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunar is a rolling-release, source-based Linux distribution for advanced users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You begin by installing the &lt;em&gt;lunar core,&lt;/em&gt; a minimal command-line only system, with the tools to build the full experience you want. From there, you create your own customized system built entirely from source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stable&quot;&gt;STABLE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use up-to-date software with very little changes from upstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;flexible&quot;&gt;FLEXIBLE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;em&gt;lunar&lt;/em&gt; package management system is written entirely is bash, and it’s both powerful and easy to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fast&quot;&gt;FAST&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware optimizations will make your system quick and responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bloat-free&quot;&gt;BLOAT-FREE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear choices for optional dependencies will ensure a system that only contains what you ask for.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This part is important - who are we trying to attract? Lunar can be good for many people, but we need a focus. Can beginners install and maintain Lunar? Do we want developers and sysadmins looking for detailed control over their system? Users with older computers looking to optimize their system? Distro hoppers looking for something new? Do we explain what makes Lunar different from other distros? Are we a de-bloated version of Gentoo? Are we an advanced version of Linuxfromscratch? sample text below: Lunar is a rolling-release, source-based Linux distribution for advanced users. You begin by installing the lunar core, a minimal command-line only system, with the tools to build the full experience you want. From there, you create your own customized system built entirely from source code. STABLE We use up-to-date software with very little changes from upstream. FLEXIBLE Our lunar package management system is written entirely is bash, and it’s both powerful and easy to learn. FAST Hardware optimizations will make your system quick and responsive. BLOAT-FREE Clear choices for optional dependencies will ensure a system that only contains what you ask for.</summary></entry></feed>